bluecava.com 2012-06-09

# BlueCava - Privacy Policy

**BlueCava Online Privacy Policy**

May 21, 2012 (this is the date of the most recent version of our policy.) We will modify the policy from time to time. Please check back for updates.

This privacy policy covers data collected by BlueCava for the purposes of online advertising and detection and prevention of fraud on the Internet.   A common complaint about privacy policies is they can be long, difficult to understand and include too much “legalese”. We have tried to explain what we do in simple, understandable language, and add a little humor at the same time. We welcome your comments.

We understand that how the Internet works, and how data is collected and used for online advertising can be a little complicated and difficult to understand. Our goal with this privacy policy is to help you understand what we do, how we do it, that what we do isn’t scary, and the options we provide you. The basis of our business is identifying devices (currently computers, cell phones, television set-top boxes and gaming consoles) that are connected to certain sites on the Internet. After identifying these machines, we collect data about those devices. The data we collect is generally used for the following: to deliver more relevant advertising, to measure the effectiveness of advertising and to reduce fraud on the Internet.  We think these are all good things, as long as we do them the right way, we are transparent in how we do them and provide you with choices.

Some people don’t like targeted ads.  If you’d like to stop BlueCava from collecting data about your device for targeted advertising, click [here](http://www.bluecava.com/preferences/ "Preferences") to opt-out. If you opt-out, you’ll still receive ads, they just won’t be tailored to your interests.

**Personal Information You Provide to Us**

Sometimes people come to our Website and fill out a form. They might give us their name, postal address, email address and/or phone number. We hope that lots of people do this because we use these registrations to qualify you as a potential customer. Then we’ll send you witty BlueCava newsletters, white papers, and marketing materials. We promise that we will follow the law with what we send you. We use this information only to respond to these requests or inquiries. We do not provide this information to third parties unless we need help with the request, likely because they can do it better or faster, or we’re busy checking out locations for our new tropical subsidiary.

If you are a BlueCava customer and use the BlueCava Website, maybe you don’t want us to contact you for marketing purposes. If that is the case, let us know by email, mail, fax or phone. The easiest way to opt-out of receiving these emails is to contact us by email at [info@bluecava.com](mailto:info@bluecava.com).

**Personal Information We Collect from Third Parties** ****

We collect personal information from other Websites or business that have received your consent to share your personal information with third parties like BlueCava for online marketing purposes. This information may include your name, postal address, email address, and/or telephone number. We do not collect Sensitive Information (see below).  We are very careful about how we use this information, and how we protect it. We store this personal information only in our secure servers. We do not store personal information in cookies.

**Non-Personal Information We Collect**

We collect non-personal information from Websites that use our Device Identification and Reputation services such as our customer’s sites or our partner sites. We anonymously collect data over time and across these sites for the purpose of creating interest based audience segments.  Examples of audience segments include sports enthusiasts, fashion shoppers, in market car buyers, etc…

We also collect non-personal information from third party data providers.  These are companies that collect anonymous demographic data, online and offline interest data, and shopping history data. They use that data to group people into audience segments. They share those audience segments with us.

**Sensitive Information  
**  
BlueCava does not collect sensitive information, including sensitive health or financial data.  This is information like health conditions, financial account numbers, etc…  This is the potentially scary stuff, and we stay away from it.

**Children  
**  
We do not target or create audience segments targeted at children under the age of thirteen (13).  We may collect data from a computer being used by someone who is under 13, and may use that data for creating interest based audience segments for advertising purposes. We are unable to prevent this since we don’t collect data with the intent of identifying children under the age of 13.

**Device Identification**

BlueCava has developed device identification technology that enables us to identify devices on the Internet.  In order to do this, we collect non-personal information about your device and Web browser when you visit one of our partner Websites.  The type of information we collect includes the type of device, IP address, browser version, time zone, the fonts installed on your device, browser plug-ins and various other properties of your device/browser. We do not collect browsing history stored in your device (aka history sniffing) as part of this process. The collected information is put into a “snapshot” and is sent to our servers each time you visit one of our partner Websites.  The servers use the information to create a unique Device ID for every device and to “match” the device to the snapshots we receive from our partners. The cool thing is, this stuff varies enough from computer to computer than we can uniquely identify devices (very few look alike).  We can only collect this information when our software is included in a software application, is on a Website, or in an online ad.

Unlike in the old days when the family used to gather around the one radio for news and entertainment (and warmth–vacuum tubes get hot!), the average 21st century household requires multiple devices for both work and play.  When we use snapshots to create a unique Device ID, we are also able to group related devices into “households” based on strong, common characteristics among the snapshots, like IP addresses.  By understanding these households, we can help our customers understand how devices are related so they can deliver content personalized to you based on your interests gathered from all your devices, no matter which device you are using and not just your primary device.

**Cookies**

We like cookies. Chocolate Chip is our favorite. Lots of people are scared of Internet cookies, but without them, the Internet would be a lot harder to use. Cookies are small text files that can be used by a Website to store information on a users’ machine and later retrieve it. We think our technology is really neat because it doesn’t require us to use cookies to identify devices.  However, in certain cases we may use cookies (aka browser cookies), Flash and/or HTML5 cookies to speed up the process of identifying the machine.  This allows us to identify a device faster, which can be good for everybody. We don’t store any personal information in cookies. Which of these technologies we use depends upon our customers/partners.  We require them to provide notice of which technologies they use on their Website.

**Web Beacons**

We may collect or share information with other Websites using Web beacons. Some people call Web beacons “1×1 image pixels”.  If the Internet guru’s are trying to confuse us, it’s working.  A Web beacon is just a link to another Website that enables two Websites to share information.  We use these with some customers/partners to share information.

**Uses of Non-Personal Information**

As BlueCava identifies devices, we also collect non-personal information. We use that information for a couple of purposes: to create anonymous audience segments for targeted advertising, to report on the effectiveness of online advertising campaigns, to deliver personalized content and services on Websites, and to reduce fraud on the Internet.

**Uses of Personal Information**

BlueCava collects personal information in order to associate Internet connected devices with anonymous, non-personally identifiable categories of information (audience segments) that can be used for online advertising. That’s a mouthful. Let us put it in layman’s terms.  Let’s say you have loyalty cards for your favorite stores.  When you sign up, you agree to let the company collect data for marketing purposes.  They use your shopping data and the email address you provide to associate you to various anonymous audience segments, things like “golf enthusiast” or “buys shoes a lot”.  We work with them to associate an Internet connected computer to those audience segments.

**Information Sharing**

BlueCava sells the data we collect. The first kind of data is the unique identity of a device. The second kind of data we sell is the data about the device, including the behavior of that device on certain sites. The data we sell helps our customers fight online fraud and provides better online ad targeting, two noble causes we think. We might combine our data with the data of others to make us even better at this.

BlueCava may share your information, including personal information with “Business Partners”. BlueCava carefully selects the Business Partners we share personal information with. These business partners typically have access to personal information and use the personal information we provide to associate marketing data with devices. We require the Business Partners we share personal information with to follow the same privacy practices we do, and to provide consumers with an opt-out. When we share personal information with them, we require them to protect that information as carefully as we do (since they already personal information, they’re already protecting it).

**Information Security and Retention**

The device identification and device reputation data that BlueCava collects is stored in the BlueCava network database. The device identification, personal and non-personal information we collect for online behavioral advertising (OBA) purposes is retained for up to two (2) years. As part of these OBA services, we also collect aggregated ad delivery and reporting data. This limited type of aggregated advertising performance data is kept indefinitely. The information we collect for fraud prevention and detection is kept indefinitely.

Access to customer information is restricted to authorized personnel. In other words, we take guarding our data seriously. Our servers are designed to be secure. Plus we’ve adopted a bunch of security procedures designed to prevent our data from being seen or stolen by a cabal of unauthorized bad guys. This should make you feel better. Here are some of the steps we take.

  * access to our computing facilities is controlled by high-tech electronic access keys. And it’s supplemented by a human security staff who are really big and mean looking. They have scars and may be packing.
  * we transmit our data using encryption protocols.
  * data access is based on the principle of least privilege. This is too complicated to explain in a bullet point.
  * access to our services is controlled two ways- password based authentication and network firewall settings.
  * application layer controls are designed to prevent other customers from getting at data that is private. So we guess you could say that at BlueCava privacy, not piracy, rules.
  * all the peeps that work at BlueCava and who have access to data are subject to our company’s policies that prohibit the unauthorized transmission of data to third parties. We don’t mess around when it comes to data.
  * no method of electronic storage or transmission is 100% secure. You see this in the movies and on TV all the time. Plus, as our lawyers point out quite emphatically and please note the capitalization for emphasis, WE WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY UNAUTHORIZED ACCESS OR USE OR ANY DAMAGES INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, CONSEQUENTIAL OR OTHER DAMAGES CAUSED BY THIRD PARTIES.

**Choices**

We think targeted advertising is a good thing. But we understand that some people don’t want data collected about them online. In addition, we’re supportive of industry self-regulatory principles for online behavioral advertising. So if you like pina coladas and getting caught in the rain but don’t want anyone to know it, we can help you opt-out so we won’t tell any of our customers that you like Jimmy Buffet.

When you choose to opt-out of tracking, as we recognize the device from one Website to another, we will no longer share behavioral advertising data with third parties. Of course, we don’t let you opt out-of us gathering information related to fighting online fraud, because if we did, the fraudsters would have a field day.

To opt-out from other companies that BlueCava may share information with, or other companies that provide online behavioral advertising services, you can opt-out at the following online advertising industry Websites.

  * The Digital Advertising Alliance Website, [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).
  * The Network Advertising Initiative Website, [www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/).

**Important Information**

**Digital Advertising Alliance**

BlueCava adheres to the Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising ([www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/)). The DAA offers a Consumer Choice Page (opt-out) and other privacy tools and resources.

**Internet Advertising Bureau**

BlueCava is a member of the Internet Advertising Bureau ([www.iab.net](http://www.iab.net/)).

**Legal and Other Disclosures  
**  
We may share personal information when we believe such action is appropriate to comply with the law (e.g., legal process or a statutory authorization); to enforce or apply our customer agreements; to initiate, render, bill, and collect for services; to protect our rights or property, or to protect users of those services from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful use of, or subscription to, such services; or if we reasonably believe that an emergency involving immediate danger of death or serious physical injury to any person requires disclosure of communications or justifies disclosure of information without delay.

**How to Contact Us** ****

If you have any questions or concerns regarding this statement, you have general or technical questions about our privacy practices and features or you have complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor, you should first contact our Privacy Officer at [privacy@bluecava.com](mailto:privacy@bluecava.com) or even by snail mail.

BlueCava  
Attn: Privacy Policy Guru  
131 Innovation Drive  
Suite 250  
Irvine, CA 92617

**Why Device Identification and Device Reputation Is Good for Consumers and Good for Society Too**

Device identification and device reputation are important because they can help fight fraud and can help provide more targeted, more relevant advertising. By knowing the identity of a device, folks can determine if that device has been used in a not so appropriate way. Here’s an example. Let’s say a bad guy wants to commit fraud, stalk people or pretend to be someone that he/she is not. If we know the identity of this connected device and this device tries to commit not so appropriate behavior again, BlueCava can recognize the device as the evildoer) and can help shut off access to it. On the flip side of the ledger, if a device has done something like making a lot of legitimate online purchases then that device may get special treatment when it visits a site where it might buy something else.

Here’s the advertising portion of the business. As almost everyone knows, advertising drives much of the free content we see online as well as a big part of our economy. Many people claim to hate advertising until they are looking for something to buy. Ever notice how you never pay attention to car ads until you’re in the market for a car? You get the point. So with BlueCava, we help you get ads that are relevant rather than ads that are shall we say more generic, and/or irrelevant. Advertisers buy audiences and with our device data we can help accumulate audiences more efficiently. We also help advertisers eliminate waste because ads are served to devices that actually can buy something. This means advertisers can spend their money more effectively to get a better return on investment. Why serve an ad to a fraudster or a bot (a robot) when there’s no chance that it can ever buy anything? Why should advertisers pay for online clicks that are being generated by machines or by click farms in the third world? By improving the overall efficiency of the ad marketplace, we’ll see more advertisers spending more dollars on advertising programs that work better. And that’s good for everyone.

In our view, rooting out fraud and providing better online targeting makes our economy more efficient and more productive. We think that companies should get what they pay for and that consumers should not have to bear the indirect burden of fraud and waste. It’s pretty straightforward.

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time.  Our Privacy Policy was last updated on May 21, 2012.
